Simon Synnes

Ålesund, Møre og Romsdal, Norway

simonsynnes@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/simonsynnes

Summary

I do software development on a daily basis. Additionally, I dedicate significant time to cyber security, particularly focusing on penetration testing and offensive security.

OSCP, PNPT and eJPT certified.

Experience using industry standard tools and techniques to include: Metasploit, Covenant, Burp Suite, SQLMap, Gobuster, Hashcat, John the Ripper, Impacket, NTLMrelay, Nmap, Proxychains, SSH tunnels, Ligolo-ng. Always working towards improving my skills and abilities.

Medium: https://medium.com/@simonsynnes Github: https://github.com/simonsynnes

Experience

LEXTO Full Stack Developer

Lexto AS

Aug 2022 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Full Stack Developer

Byggmann Gruppen AS Dec 2020 - Aug 2022 (1 year 9 months)

Global Technical Support Engineer

Inmarsat

Aug 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 5 months)

R Information Technology Support Consultant

Rolls-Royce

Oct 2015 - Jun 2018 (2 years 9 months)

-- Ground Handler

Aviator Airport Alliance AB Oct 2015 - Sep 2016 (1 year)

IT Apprentice

Kongsberg Maritime
Jun 2013 - Aug 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Education

Norwegian University of Science and Technology (NTNU)

Bachelor's degree, dataingeniør 2016 - 2019

Home Lab

Nov 2023 - Jan 2024

Høgskolen i Ålesund (HiÅ)

Forkurs for ingeniør- og sivilingeniørutdanning 2015 - 2016

Ålesund VGS

IKT Fagbrev

Alesund VGS

IKT Fagbrev Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

Licenses & Certifications

ITIL v3 Foundation

- Tools of the Trade: Linux and SQL Coursera
 ERUNP2W22WQP
- **Google Cybersecurity Certificate** Google
- Junior Penetration Tester (eJPTv2) INE Security (FKA eLearnSecurity)
 86741855
- Practical Network Penetration Tester (PNPT) TCM Security 89157735
- OffSec Certified Professional (OSCP) OffSec 95919444

Skills

Cloud Security • OSCP • Reconnaissance • TCM • Metasploit • Burp Suite • Kali Linux • Host & Networking Penetration Testing • Incident Response • Penetration Testing